[Music]
hey everyone this is a very quick update
to the investigation from Sunday on
London real and David Icke
I'm busily working on a few other bigger
pieces about kind of the wider issues
about free speech accountability
I don't know ended up doing like daily
updates about what's going on but the
David Icke interview happened on Sunday
and I think it's worth updating what
happened and there's some really
interesting stuff quite amusing stuff
actually so if you haven't seen the
investigation go and check it out this
will help make a lot more sense and also
there's a deeper story here of sort of
we've talked on the channel before about
collective intelligence sort of networks
of collective intelligence and that they
are kind of stepping up I've been
contacted by dozens of people I'd say
since I put the out the investigation
kind of online open-source detective
stuff which is really great I almost put
something out on the day of the
interview about this I didn't for that
reason I didn't want to get kind of
involved in like a blow-by-blow but
Brian Rose the interviewer on London
rail have been putting out for days how
the Icke interview is going to be at a
secret location he was worried they
might get raided he put out this one on
the day from the secret bunker okay we
are literally in the bunker here I'm
about to head in and start this
broadcast soon with David Icke kind of
have our whole crew has been set up here
making sure everything happens in the
background and just want to make sure we
had a lockdown place so didn't worry
about anything stopping us I mean these
days there's so many forces trying to
make sure this broadcast doesn't happen
so someone got in touch and said hang on
this secret bunker looks a lot like the
London real building itself from this
previous video all right he is almost
midnight here at London real world
headquarters I'm walking out tonight
had midnight and I've been here since I
think 8 a.m. and so I just wanted to
give you a little taste of what it takes
which you must do in order to be an
entrepreneur someone else sent me the
floor plan for the building that London
real is in so you can see the same
typeface and also this picture from the
white-collar Factory brochure which I
will put in the show notes you look very
closely you'll see that s is actually
the service floor or the the basement of
the building so I also want to update
that in the investigation I played a
clip by someone who'd found out that the
link to the independent digital freedom
platform just play the clip that shows
that Brian Rose said that this was gonna
be independent of London real the point
is is this is a separate entity that
lives on past us that is independently
funded so we don't draw any of this
money this is set up as an independent
platform so that has nothing to do with
London real so they discovered that when
the digital freedom platform which is
inside the London real website was a
plugin for film that was coming from the
dailymotion site so for the IKE
interview it wasn't coming from
dailymotion
so I want to update on that it seems to
have been coming from a company called
des cast which is based in Silicon
Valley so it was paid for streaming no
idea how much it actually cost a stream
from there we don't know what the
figures would be either so yesterday
London real put out this film called we
did it over a million love is the answer
but now we must prepare for war we
unpack this because it shows up so many
of the issues that we're dealing with at
the moment in the information ecology
but also in the wider culture so Rose
put out this about the the studio and
the funding campaign the truth is is it
I can't always tell you what's going on
the scenes I can't so there were a lot
of people questioning what we were doing
and questioning the technology we were
using but the truth is is that we've got
a little control the opposition out
there if you didn't notice okay we got
people in come the inside that don't
have our best interests so I gotta do a
little head fake every now and then I
hope you guys appreciate that and that
means sometimes pretending we're using
certain tech and using other technology
pretending we're going to one studio and
going to another studio trust me we're
doing this for your protection all right
this is so we don't get shut down and
ruin your Sunday or ruin your messaging
that could ruin your life so every now
and then we're gonna do something and I
just need you to trust me is what I'm
saying all right now I'm assuming
because a lot of people had noticed
these details about the location about
the stream he had to say something about
it but calling it a head-fake is I think
really it's very interesting I'm not a
lawyer but I don't think that's a very I
don't think that's a terribly smart
thing to be telling people of just
giving you money legally doesn't seem
very wise to me but we'll see what
happens but there's another really
interesting angle to this that I want to
focus on I'll start by playing the clip
from that film honestly now is when the
war starts now how can love bring us war
well there's gonna be a lot of people
that want to take us down there's gonna
be a lot of people and they're gonna
start with reputation the business with
London real with all of our stuff and
they're gonna start pairing us together
and saying nasty things about us that
you're gonna say that can't be Brian
that can't be London real well guess
what they're gonna start saying it so we
have to be strong we have to be strong
now and expect it and that's what we're
doing now we're expecting it but we need
to make the army even bigger right now
we need to build because we can see
what's happening even though we've had
the largest broadcast in human history
of a conversation that's not enough to
show people we're doing something
important we're still gonna fight so we
are here in for the fight
hashtag London real army has never been
so strong so this is the most perfect
example of what Venkatesh
has called the internet of beefs in this
amazing article that he put out on
ribbon farmer while ago so I'll put the
link in the show notes to follow it it's
really it's a really smart examination
of how exponential tech and the tech
platforms like the incentive structure
of the tech platforms have created what
he calls the Internet of beefs which is
this sort of degeneration into warfare
like online warfare because it rewards
that tactic and he he describes it like
this I'm going to read from the article
a beef only thinker is someone you
cannot simply talk to anything that is
not an expression of pure unqualified
support for whatever they are doing or
saying is received as a mark of
disrespect and a provocation to conflict
from there you can only crash into honor
based conflict mode or back away and
disengage so he compares it to crash
only programming in in internet language
it's a beautiful brilliant article
because it also illustrates what is
going on in the wider culture I think at
the moment we're talking about online
warfare I don't think it's gonna stay
that way I think a lot of people who are
kind of sounding the alarm or right to
sound the alarm so it and it basically
shows how all of the tech platforms a
kind of degenerating into this
information warfare all-out battle
between those who are willing to play
this game of nights and MOOCs and he
describes nights and MOOCs as the
structure of the Internet of beefs is
shaped by high profile beefs between
charismatic celebrity knights loosely
affiliated with various Citadel like
strongholds peopled by opt-in armies of
MOOCs the vast majority of the ng the
vast majority of the energy of the
conflict lies in interchangeable mooks
facing off against each other
loosely along lines indicated by the
Knights they follow in enumerable
battles that play out every minute
across the internet of beefs now
high-profile examples of that I would
say Candice Owens have a look at her
Twitter feed since the beginning of the
pandemic very clearly playing that game
but the incentive structure rewards that
game that's that that's the point and on
a deeper level
what this is
and we put out quite a lot of films
around this it's the underlying source
code of our current system weaponized by
exponential tech is zero some thinking
and is leading to self terminating
outcomes and I think this is just being
accelerated by all the dynamics at the
that the pandemic is bringing up its
weaponizing division its hijacking our
limbic systems it's optimizing for
engagement which means optimizing for
passion rather than reason all of those
things so we like I said we've talked
about this on the channel quite a lot I
highly recommend going to check out the
war on sense making peace with Daniel
SHM attenberger deep code with Jordan
green Hall and the interview with
Douglas rushkoff
and a plaque clip from that right now we
are living with technologies that are
intentionally designed to make us
fearful to make us panic to put us back
into our brainstem to avoid our higher
human thinking and our even our
mammalian thinking and then sometimes
we're trying to connect with other
people over devices that are designed to
make us hate and fear the other person
designed to a dict us to the tech
designed to get us to interact with
non-player characters algorithms rather
than other people and then we wonder why
we feel bad you know if you live in a in
a digital haunted house that's designed
by Stanford behavioral engineers to make
you hate to make you fear what do you
think's gonna happen you know it's just
a split and then you grow up in it as a
child I mean what do you think's gonna
happen to those brains what do you
think's gonna happen to those to those
hearts also check out Tristan Harris who
used to work at Google he's got a TED
talk he's kind of known now as the
conscience of Silicon Valley because he
has sort of been sounding the alarm for
a while so this sort of deeper question
of how all of the most pathological
forces of game a like the present
underlying source code of
are being accelerated under the impact
of the pandemic is what I'm going to
unpack properly in the next film I don't
see a good outcome for I think it's
worse in America I think we have some
especially in the information warfare
space I think we're in a slightly better
position in the UK I'll try and unpack
why I think that is as well because
that's worth understanding but the
bigger question and there's other
questions I'll unpack as well so some of
the other criticisms of the
investigation it's like how we hold each
other accountable without getting
dragged into this same Internet of beefs
zero-sum dynamic so this kind of idea
that we used to have the this idea of
the Dunbar number so the Dunbar number
is 150 people in tribes and Robin Dunbar
at the University of Oxford basically
found that usually groups would start to
fractionate and divide when they got to
150 people looked through history and
that was basically the optimum tribal
number and the reason for that is or one
of the main reasons is that they've
become self policing through gossip and
through conversation about each other
you didn't create niches for sociopathic
behavior to thrive because you would be
able to hold 150 people is about as many
of those you can personally know and
then be able to compute all of the
different relationships between those
people so there's an X if you think
about it with a number of people you get
this sort of exponential linkage number
of people so it's not just knowing that
many faces it's also knowing all of the
relationships between them so you would
have a self policing system within the
Dunbar number as soon as we scaled our
society up beyond that what Jordan Hall
is called the blue church again watch
the decode documentary to kind of
understand his frame which i think is
the best most interesting most useful
frame for understanding what we're going
through as soon as you scale that out
what you end up doing is creating niches
for sociopathic behavior and you
actually start rewarding that
sociopathic behavior that's the worst
thing is that you've basically created a
society that rewards screwing other
people over that actually writes it into
the source code of the companies as soon
as you say you know your your your role
is
to maximize profit for your shareholders
you have no moral obligations to anyone
else that's for me the big picture
situation that we're in right now and
that seems to be accelerating under the
impact of the pandemic so yeah lots of
other things to talk about in future
films I'm working on now including the
big question about the information
ecology I'm sort of putting out my take
on it specifically focused around Brian
Rose London real David Icke because I
think that's a really I think it's the
most fascinating example of free speech
responsibilities tech platforms
heavy-handed censorship continuing and
making the problem worse but what could
a system of accountability look like for
the digital age like some I don't know
what that means I don't know war that's
what that looks like so we will explore
that in future films and I'll talk to
other people and see what they think so
see you see rebel wisdom was set up to
make sense of the world at a deeper
level than the mainstream media it was
built for these times of crisis and
change which is why we want to do what
we can to meet the challenge of the
times more films and also for our rebel
wisdom members weekly sense-making calls
with our amazing interviewees and also
we're introducing the wisdom gym a place
to practice some of the skills that
we've talked about on the channel thanks
for watching and see you soon
[Music]